Guide to the John Lowenthal Papers TAM.190
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series I: Alger Hiss Research Files, 1934-2003
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Alger Hiss (pp. 253-337), Jan 22, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Nathan Witt (pp. 338-400), Jan 5, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Ralph de Toledano (pp. 401-448), Apr 6, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, John Francis Cronin and Mr. and Mrs. Donald Hiss (pp. 449-510), undated, Apr 8, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Mike, Pat and Raymond Catlett (pp. 511-541), Apr 8, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Ramos Feehan, Harold Rosenwald and Mr. Doyle (pp. 542-652), Apr 26, 1977-Apr 27, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Edward Murtagh, Malcolm Crowley, Isaac Don Levine and David Zablodowsky (pp 653-652a), May 13, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Robert Stripling and Congressman Herbert (pp. 653a-764), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Vincent Reno and Sam Krieger (pp. 765-859), Aug 15, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Harold Shapero and Ordman Clubb (pp. 860-981), Sep 7, 1977, Sep 15, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Margaret Halsey and Alger Hiss, Gussie Feinstein (pp. 982-1139/39), Nov 17, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Interviews, Vincent Shaw (pp. 1113-1164), Mar 18, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Turner, Catherine: Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - University of Texas at Austin, School of Law: Re: Alger Hiss, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Van Doren, Mark: (Includes Whittaker Chambers Correspondence), 1926, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, Jan 2002-Apr 2002 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander: Re: Court Case, May 2002-Oct 2002 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Venona: Documents, 1950-1956 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Venona: Re: "Ales", 1956, 1996, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Volkogonov, Dmitri, undated, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Vorontsov, Yuri: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Weinstein, Allen: Re: Perjury, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Weissberger, L. Arnold: Re: Hiss, 1965-1978 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Werchen, Raymond: Writings Re: Hiss, 1973, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, undated, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Whitman, Alden, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Zeligs, Meyer: Correspondence, 1962-1965, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Zeligs, Meyer: Re: Friendship and Fratricide, undated, 1963-1970 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1942-2003.
  - Abt, John J., 1953, 1958, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Adams,: "Nothing to Fear but Fear Itself," Typescript (British Broadcasting Service), 0000 (Box 6, Folder 1a)
  - Adler, Mortimer: Correspondence, Nov 1, 1976-Dec 1, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Aldrich, Richard: Re: The Haunted Wood, May 1, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Alger Hiss Case in America and Russia (JL): Typescript, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Alger Hiss: The Perfect Victim: Correspondence and Typescript, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Alger Hiss and William A. Reuben v. U.S. Department of Justice et al., Sep 2, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Allen, George: Re: J. Edgar Hoover, Homosexuality, 1946, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Andrew, Christophe, 1999-2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Association of American Indian Affairs: Memorandum, Jun 4, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bannerman, Robert L.: Handwritten Notes, re:, Mar 30, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Barksdale, Calvert: Seaver Books, re: Coram Nobis Manuscript, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bogert, Carroll, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bonin, Richard: 60 Minutes, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Book Two: Unsigned Typescript, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Botstein, Leon, 1981, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Boughton, James: Articles and Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Brent, Jonathan: Yale University Press, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Breyer, Henry W. Jr.: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Brick, Richard: Correspondence, undated, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Brick, Richard: Silo Cinema, 1976-1981, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Brown, William Adams: Correspondence, Feb 6, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bush, Flora Wilhelm: "A Discussion of the Case of Alger Hiss", 1979 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cammer, Harold I.: Letter to the Editor re: Lionel Trilling/Chambers, Apr 7, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Cantwell, Robert, 1973, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Carlsen, Carl E.: Correspondence, 1975, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Cass, Stewart: Correspondence, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Chaly, Ingeborg: "Rhetorical Discretion and Legal Constraints in Jury Instructions: A Comparative Analysis of the Two Charges to the Jury in the Alger Hiss Perjury Trials", 1981 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Chamberlain, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, Apr 21, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Chambers, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, Jan 19, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Homosexuality, 1948-1950, 1974-1977, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Investigation of, Nov 1948 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Notes for Book, re:, Sep 6, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Notes re: Break with Communist Party, Feb 13, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Chambers, Whittaker: Writings in The Saturday Evening Post, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Chandler, Tertius: Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Clark, Blair: The Nation, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Clubb, Oliver Edmund, 1977-1978, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Cold War International History Project: "The Hiss Case and Soviet Archives," Typescript (drafts), Dec 17, 1993-Mar 16, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Cold War International History Project: "The Hiss Case and Soviet Archives," Typescript (drafts), Mar 18, 1994-Apr 25, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Commentary: Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Committee on Un-American Activities, U.S. House of Representatives (HUAC): Pamphlets, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A., 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Compton, James: "Anti-Communism in American Life Since the Second World War" and Correspondence, 1973, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Connelley, Earl J: Affidavit, Mar 12, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: General, undated, 1962-1963, 1970-1999 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: Re: John Earl Haynes, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: Re: William A. Reuben's Writings, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Counterattack, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Cowley, Michael: Clippings and Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Craig, Bruce: "A Matter of Espionage: Alger Hiss, Harry Dexter White and Igor Gouzenko-The Canadian Connection Reassessed," Typescript, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Craig, Bruce: Re: Opening Hiss Grand Jury Records, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Craig, Bruce: Writings, undated, 1990, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cronin, John F., 1940s, 1968-1980, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cross, Claude B.: "'The Assistance of Counsel for His Defense': Is This Becoming a Meaningless Guarantee?" American Bar Association Journal, Dec 1952 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Currie, Laughlin, 1940-1959, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Davies, John: Correspondence, Jun 2, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Davis, John F.: Handwritten Notes, re:, Dec 30, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Dean, John, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Douglas, William O., 1976, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Doyle, Jerome, 1948, 1977-1978, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Dreyfus Case and the Hiss Case: Points of Similarity and Points of Difference, Typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Eddy, George: Chambers-Hiss, Typescript, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Einstein, Albert: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Elsten, David: Hiss/Venona Documentary, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Elsten, David: Thames Television, Inc., 1978-1983 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Espionage Law: Handwritten Notes, re:, undated, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Eye of a Bird: Play re: Hiss, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - FBI: FOIA Request re: John Lowenthal, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Field, Noel: Article and Handwritten Notes, Re:, 1993-1994, 2000-2002 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Footnote on a Historic Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, No. 78 Civ. 3433 (JL) (Nation Institute), 1983 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Gates, John: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Glazer, Nathan: The National Interest, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Global American Television, Inc.: Correspondence, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Gordievsky, Oleg A.: Article and Clippings, re:, 1990, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Gorizontov, Leonid: East European Scientific and Information Agency, undated, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Griffin, Kevin W.: Correspondence and Handwritten Notes, re:, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: Correspondence, 1976, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: "The Discrepancies in the Evidence," Typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Gwynn, Beatrice: Translation of Augusto Marcelli's Article in Paese Sera re: Hiss' Visit to Italy, Sep 27, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Halperin, Morton: Re: Herbert Hoover, Official and Confidential Files, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Halperin, Morton: Re: Wiretapping, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Hamilton, James: Correspondence, 1979, 1982, 1999-2003 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Hamilton, James: Writings, undated, 1981, 1993-1999 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Handwritten Notes: Re: Hiss, 1950-1979, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Haury, Agnese Nelms (formerly Agnese Nelms Lindley and Agnese Nelms Lockwood): Correspondence and Memoranda, 1974-1981, 1992-2001 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Heller, Howard: Correspondence, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (I), undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (II), undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (III), undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Heller, Howard: "The Hiss Case Hoax," Typescript (IV), undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Hiss, Alger: Re: "Ales"/Mars, Jan 2, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1961-1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1967-1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1978, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hiss, Alger: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Files I, 1940s (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hiss, Alger: FOIA II, 1940s (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hiss, Alger: FOIA III, 1940s (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hiss, Alger: FBI Report, 1941-1942, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Hiss, Alger: Law Talk, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Hiss, Alger: McCarthy Era, Notes re:, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Hiss, Alger: Nye Committee, Hiss Questions Bernard Baruch, 1990s (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Hiss, Alger: Obituaries, Nov 16, 1996-Nov 19, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hiss, Alger: Re: Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Hiss, Alger: Yalta Conference, Articles re:, undated, Nov 1955 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. U.S.A., 1950 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. U.S.A., 1952 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 1-209), Nov 4, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 210-440)), Nov 5, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Mrs. Esther Chambers, Direct (pp. 441-640), Nov 17, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Mrs. Esther Chambers, Direct (pp. 641-715), Nov 17, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 716-829), Nov 17, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 830-1061), Nov 17, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, Direct (pp. 1062-1290), Feb 18, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss v. Whittaker Chambers, In the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland Civil No. 4176, Deposition of Whittaker Chambers, (pp. 1291-1382), Mar 25, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: Alger Hiss, Richard Strasburger and Besse Brown Strasberger v. Robert E. Hampton et al., 1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Baltimore Depositions, Notes, 1976, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Baltimore Exhibits (Lowenthal reference file, mostly defense materials: memos, correspondence, background on Woodstock typewriter, etc.), 1948-1949, 1962-1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Bykov, Boris, 1945, 1949, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: Catlett, Mike and Pat, 1949, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Chambers, Whittaker and Esther, undated, 1945-1952 (Box 10, Folder 4a)
  - Hiss Case: Character Witnesses, Individuals and Organizations, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Collins, Henry, 1948, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Davis, John, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: "Die Deutsche Regierung...": Aide-Memoire, on 1930s Trade (in German; photostat; labeled 611.6231/987), Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Dulles, John Foster, Jul 1, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Fearon, Edwin, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: FBI Memos, 1948-1949, 1956, 1963-1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Government Exhibits (List and misc. copies, 1st and 2nd trials?), undated, 1938-1949 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Hiss Case: Inslerman, Felix, Jan 21, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 12a)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Appendix to the Brief for the Petitioner, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Brief for the Petitioner, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Hiss Case: In the Matter of Alger Hiss, Brief of the Bar Counsel, May 1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for Petitioner-Appellant, Nov 30, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for Respondent-Appellee, USA, Jul 15, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Brief for the United States in Opposition, Oct 1983 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum in Support of Petitioner's Motion to Grant Writ of Coram Nobis, Jul 8, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum of Law in Opposition to Petitioner's Application for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis, Jul 27, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Memorandum of Law in Opposition to Petitioner's Application for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis and to Petitioner's Application for an Evidentiary Hearing and Discovery, Nov 20, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Opinion of Richard Owen, Jul 15, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Reargument and Rehearing En Banc, Feb 24, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, Jun 17, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Petition for Writ of Error Coram Nobis, Jul 27, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Reply Brief for Petitioner-Appellant, Feb 9, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Hiss Case: In Re: Alger Hiss, Reply Brief in Support of Petition for a Writ of Certiorari, Sep 30, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Hiss Case: Investigators, 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: Jurors, 1949, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Lane, Chester, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: New England Spectrochemical Laboratories, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: Oral Testimonies, Notes, 1940s, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: Pigman, Ward, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, Amicus Curia Brief of the Boston Bar Association, May 7, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, Application, Jan 7, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: Reinstatement to Massachusetts State Bar, On Report by a Justice of the Supreme Court for Suffolk County, [1975] (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: Russian Archives, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Case: Schmahl, Horace, undated, 1941-1952, 1971-1975 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Case: Time, Life, Fortune, Editors, 1930-1959 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Appeal from a Judgment of the District Court for the Southern District of New York, Dec 7, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Brief for Appellant, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Memorandum in Support of Defendant's Motion for a New Trial Under Rule 33 on the Ground of Newly Discovered Evidence, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Appellant's Brief, Nov 1952 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Appendix to Appellant's Brief, Jul 22, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Consolidated Index of Record, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Petition for Rehearing, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume I, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume II, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume III, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume IV, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume V, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VI, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VII, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VIII, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume IX, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume X, Jan 25, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Second Supplemental Affidavit, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, May 31, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 6, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 9, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 14, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 20, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 23, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 28, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 30, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jul 6, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Woodstock Typewriter, 1940s (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The Hiss Case Revisited (JL): Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - The Hiss Case Revisited (JL): Typescript, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Introduction (Chapter 1), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Coram Nobis, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Drafts and Comments, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Notes, re:, 1982, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Russia, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): The Typewriter, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Whittaker Chambers' Homosexuality, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Hiss, Tony: Re: Laughing Last, undated, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Hiss, Tony: Writings, 1995-1996, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Hobson, Timothy, 1949-1950, 1968, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Hofstra University: International Conference on Harry S. Truman, Apr 14, 1983-Apr 16, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Horowitz, Sol, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Howgate, James C.: HUAC Reports, Re:, Mar 1963 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Hunt, Howard: Grand Jury Testimony, May 2, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Ilyashov, Anatoli Michael: Correspondence and Letter to the Editor, 1992-1994 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Intelligence and National Security: "Venona and Alger Hiss", 2000 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Kalugin, Oleg Danielovich: Clippings and Correspondence, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Kenan, George B., 1972, 1977, 1996-1999 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Kenshaw, Alex: The Guardian, 1992-1994 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Kinsley, Michael and Arthur Lubow: "Alger Hiss and the Smoking Gun Fallacy" (Washington Monthly), Oct 1975 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Kraft, Marion: Last Will and Testament, re:, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Kraft, Marion: Motion Picture Editors, Local 771, 1978-1982 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Krieger, Sam: Chambers/Hiss, Re:, 1977-1982 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Krieger, Sam: Lawsuit Re: Perjury, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Lake, Anthony: CIA, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Lamphere, Robert J.: Book Excerpts and Notes, re:, 1983, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Leab, Daniel J.: "United We Eat: The Creation and Organization of the Unemployed Councils in 1930" (Labor History), Fall 1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Lee, Duncan, Eleanor and John: Correspondence and Letter to the Editor (New York Times), 1999 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Lee Pressman and David Witt, Typescript, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Support: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Letters to the Editor: Drafts, 1973; 1986; 1991-1993 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Letters to the Editor: Drafts, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Letters to the Editor: Drafts, 1995-2003 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Letters to the Editor: Published, 1992-2001 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Letters to the Editor: Re: Alger Hiss Obituaries, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Levin, David: Articles and Obituaries, 1976, 1979, 1993-1997 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Levin, David: Correspondence, 1993-1998 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1940-1999 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Lockwood, Manice, III: Correspondence, undated, 1950-1953, 1969-1994 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Lowe, Richard H.: Correspondence, 1976, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Lowe, Richard H.: "Fallen Warrior of Reform: Jerome N. Frank as General Counsel for the Agricultural Adjustment Administration," Class Paper, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Lowenthal, Anne: Correspondence, 1981, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Lowenthal, David: Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 15, Folder 19)